Nicholas WAN

Mobile: +65 9851 0403

Email: nicholaswan@nus.edu.sg

Skype: nicholaswan

Github: https://github.com/nicholas-wan
Online Resume: http://bit.do/nicholaswan



Personal Statement

I am Nicholas Wan, a Business Analytics undergraduate from the National University of Singapore (NUS). I am currently seeking to secure a year-long internship in a start-up in Silicon Valley, USA, from July 2019, as part of the NUS Overseas Colleges Programme. I wish to pursue a career in Healthcare Analytics, as I would like to do work that makes a positive impact on the lives of others. I am also pursuing a minor in Public Health, as I believe the knowledge acquired would be germane to Healthcare Analytics.

About me

I am an independent and motivated individual who is always willing to learn. Last summer, I worked with a group of pharmacy students on an independent project module. My partner and I created a healthcare web application which provides medical advice for users, and thereafter recommends them an active ingredient and shows them a list of products available in Singapore which contain that active ingredient. Our app, Zera is accessible at https://zera.herokuapp.com/home. We are planning to continue working on this project even after the module ends.

Additionally, I have strong leadership qualities, great time-management and organizational skills. Since high school, I have held several leadership positions: The Vice-President of Public Address in high school, as well as an executive committee member for a Programming club in a residential college in NUS, where I organized events to teach non-programming students basic programming language. I believe in applying the knowledge and skills that I have learned to contribute to the community, and I am currently conducting seminars to teach the students in my Residential College how to create their own website and basic knowledge of python.

Work Experiences

Last summer, I also did an internship at Guco Consulting, where I worked as a web developer. I developed and designed websites for four separate companies. Working together with other interns, we developed marketing strategies for these companies. Currently, I am also working on another project, to create a website to market unique handcrafted bags.

How can I contribute

I can contribute in various technical areas that require knowledge on data analytics or web development. Furthermore, I am willing and keen to learn new skills that the company requires. I believe that with my experiences, I can contribute significantly and be a great asset to the company.

Weakness

I believe in giving my best for all my work, and thus, may put myself under unnecessary pressure. However, I believe that a certain level of stress is necessary to achieve work of good quality, and I constantly remind myself to regulate the level of stress with recreational activities like badminton or swimming.

All in all, with my experiences, skill sets, strong motivation and other personal attributes, I believe that I can contribute significantly to your company and be a great addition to the company's dynamics.

Education

Aug 2017 - Present	National University of Singapore Bachelor of Science (Honors) in Business Analytics (Course details in Appendix A)	Singapore
Jan 2013 - Dec 2014	 National Junior College Singapore-Cambridge General Certificate of Education Advanced Level Subjects: Physics (A), Chemistry (A), Mathematics (A), Economics (A), General Paper (A), Project Work (A) 	Singapore
Work Experience		
Jul 2018 – Aug 2018	 Bags by Samarkyra Web Developer (Part time project) Hired as a web developer to create a website to sell unique handcrafted bags, with a vision to create employment for the minority. bagsbysamarkyra.com 	Singapore
May 2018 – Aug 2018	 Guco Consulting Group Web Developer (Internship) (Testimonial in Appendix B) Responsible for developing websites for 3 different companies 	Singapore
Mar 2017 - Apr 2017	Methodology of Studies Tutor Taught two classes of Secondary 3 Physics students	Singapore
Mar 2015 - Jan 2017	 Naval Diving Unit 2nd Sergeant Held a leadership role and oversaw a dive team Operations IC & Logistics IC 	Singapore
Scholastic Achievem	ents/Extracurricular Activities	
Aug 2017 - Present	Scholarship NUS Merit Scholarship (National University of Singapore)	Singapore
Aug 2017 - Present	Projects Zera Independent Work Project to develop a medical chatbot to provide a preliminary assessment of symptoms, and a web application to provide a platform for the comparison of active ingredients of medication (e.g paracetamol) as well as products (e.g Panadol)	Singapore
Jan 2013 - Present	 School Contributions NUS CAPTSLOCK Taught basic programming skills to students of College of Alice and Peter Tan to promote technological awareness Lightsabering with the Deaf Learned sign language and facilitated an event for the Deaf and hearing to have fun with Lightsabering Vice President of Public Address in National Junior College 	Singapore
Jan 2013 - Dec 2014	 National Junior College Awards Edusave Award for Achievement, Good Leadership and Service Edusave Good Progress Award 	Singapore

Skill Sets & Proficiency

Office Productivity Microsoft Word, PowerPoint Proficient

Microsoft Excel Intermediate

Multimedia Adobe Photoshop CS6 Intermediate

Adobe Premiere Pro Basic

Web HTML Proficient CSS Proficient

MeteorJS Basic

Database MySQL Intermediate

Mongo DB Basic

ProgrammingPythonProficientJavaProficient

R Intermediate C++ Basic

Scripting JavaScript Basic

Mac

Data Tableau Intermediate

Operating Systems Windows 10, XP Intermediate

Management Git Intermediate

Non-technical Skills Project Management Intermediate

Leadership Intermediate

Intermediate

Language Proficiency

SpokenEnglish – fluent; Mandarin – average; Japanese – averageWrittenEnglish – competent; Chinese – average; Japanese – average

Additional Information

Other activities/interests

Degree: Bachelor of Science (Honors) in Business Analytics

Cumulative Average Point: 4.75 / 5.00

Year	Level	Course Description	Grades
Mar – Jun 2017	Special Term	Programming Methodology	A-
Aug – Nov 2017	Year 1/Semester 1	Quantitative Reasoning	А
		Introduction to Business Analytics	А
		Data Structures and Algorithms I	A-
		Exploring Blogs as a Form of Communication	A-
		Computing and Society	S
		Roots and Wings- Personal and Interpersonal Effectiveness	
Jan – May 2018	Year 1/Semester 2	Calculus for Computing	A+
		Principles of Economics	A+
		Principles of Marketing	А
		Data Management and Visualisation	A-
		Nobodiness: The Self as Story	A-
		Jr Sem: Family in a Changing Singapore	CS
May – Jul 2018	Year 1/Summer	# Independent Work (Orbital)	CS
Aug – Nov 2018	Year 2/Semester 1	Decision Making Methods and Tools	In-Progress
		Linear Algebra I	In-Progress
		Data Structures and Algorithms II	In-Progress
		Environment and Civil Society in Singapore	In-Progress
		Public Health in Action	In-Progress

[#] The **Independent Work (Orbital)** allows year 1 undergraduates from all faculties to form a team of 2 and create any project within 3 months. It is an independent project and, thus, students are required to do their own research and self-study. This allows students to gain an experience of doing a self-study project. I paired up with my friend, a business analytics student, to design a healthcare web application.

NUS Grading Scale:

A+ & A (5.0); A- (4.5); B+ (4.0); B (3.5); B- (3.0); C+ (2.5); C (2.0); D+ (1.5); D (1.0); F (0)

S = Satisfactory; U = Unsatisfactory

CS = Completed Satisfactorily; CU = Completed Unsatisfactorily

EXE = Exempted; IC = Incomplete; IP = In Progress; W = Withdrawn

Work Testimonial

Guco Consulting Pte Ltd

Big Box Singapore, 1 Venture Ave, Singapore 608521 hello@gucoconsulting.com www.gucoconsulting.com

To Whom It May Concern:

I am writing this letter as a personnel reference for Nicholas Wan, who worked with us as a Web Developer Intern for a period of two months. During this short span, Nicholas completed challenging projects at a professional level, and successfully developed websites for 3 different companies. He exceeded expectations as a part-time Web Developer and was thoroughly involved in the User Interface/Experience (UI/UX) planning phase.

Nicholas is a hardworking and determined individual. He was responsible and meticulous in his work. This is shown clearly in the neatness of his coding and documentation. This made it easier for others who were working with him to follow up on his work. Furthermore, when met with tasks that were beyond his expertise he would seek solutions cleverly and resolve any difficulties he faced quickly. He is also a friendly and effective team player. This allowed him to work closely and effectively with his fellow interns in designing and implementing the websites.

As a highly motivated individual, he was always interested in learning new things, even skills which are not integral to his degree in Business Analytics, e.g. design skills on Photoshop and Adobe Illustrator. Nicholas was passionate in learning new skills and never shied away from asking interesting and in-depth questions.

I highly recommend Nicholas, and I am confident that he would be an asset to any organization he joins. With his experience and personality, I would strongly recommend him for a place in the NUS Overseas College programme or in any other esteemed organizations. Please do not hesitate to contact me, at my email hello@gucoconsulting.com, should you require any further information.

Yours Sincerely,
Sng Yi
CEO / Founder
Guco Consulting Pte Ltd.